周六\N下午5点\N　\N
婚礼前25小时
马修和马尔文坐着公交车
Marshall and marvin were taking the bus
正赶着和我们相见于长岛的旅社
On their way to long island to meet up with us.
好啦 好啦 马尔文
there, there, little marvin.
不要再哭啦
Let no more tears fall.
我们很快就能见到妈妈啦
We're gonna see mommy in no time at all.
大家好 很抱歉孩子的吵闹给你们添堵
Hello there. I'm sorry for all of the noise.
艾瑞克森家的男人们今天颇为辛苦
It's been a long day for the Eriksen boys.
这押韵是怎么回事
Uh... What's with the rhyming?
这问题真是问得好
I'm glad that you ask.
哄我儿子睡觉可不好搞
To get my son sleeping is no easy task.
几周前 我老婆担起了重任
A few weeks ago, the job fell to my wife.
我儿子哭得让人心疼得很
And as the poor baby cried out for dear life,
她把每本童话书都试了一遍
She read every book, but all were no use
最终找到一位鹅妈妈才结束灾难
Until she arrived at a mother named goose.
鹅妈妈童谣是一本英国民间童谣集
-为什么呢 马尔文  -她发现
-Why, marvin... -She noted.
这些押韵让你恹恹欲睡
...These rhymes make you tired!
从此 小马尔文有了心水
And ever since then, all young marvin's required
只需这书有押韵 他便能安静熟睡
Is one book of rhymes, and to dream land he goes.
好啦 现在咱读什么呢
Now, what shall we read?
不好了 我把书落在那辆车上了
Oh, crap, I left his book in the car!
那可真衰
That blows.
老爸\N　　　  　　 老妈\N　　 　　 浪漫史\N　　  　　　　第九季  第十一集\N
S09E11 Bedtime Stories
翻译: @小白是憎恶 @阿狸小H @毒舌的吊儿郎当\N @CIA_Kevin @云湾森川如风 @肉鸭大魔王♥@晒小花
统筹+校对+后期+时间轴+压制\N禽兽诗人肉鸭鸭 温婉词人小花花
HIMYM字幕组 倾情奉献
这回可坏大事了
Oh, no, what a bummer!
这是什么狗屎运啊
What craptastic luck!
没了马尔文的押韵书 这趟旅程注定艰苦
Without marvin's rhyme book, this ride's gonna suck!
车上有谁带了本诗集吗
Does anyone here have some poetry maybe?
或者出个主意
Or any advice?
有 别生娃就行了呀
Yeah! Don't have a baby!
要是不让小马尔文醒过来
I guess if I don't want young Marvin to wake up,
我只能自己把韵押起来
The rhymes will just have to be ones that I make up.
出口成章 七步成诗什么的都是我的菜
I'll whip up some poetry in seconds flat!
有了
Oh, I know!
这故事就叫莫斯比击球不长眼
This story's called Mosby at the bat!
泰德情路多料峭
The outlook wasn't brilliant for poor Ted's romantic life.
三十好几没人要
He was deep into his thirties, and yet, still he had no wife.
有天正把论文批
But then, one day whilst grading papers,
生活还让他不如意
Life sent him a whammy.
一个物理教授叫丽萨
A physics prof named Lisa
不久前刚到 来自迈阿密
Who'd just moved here from miami.
教授
Professor?
她面露羞涩之意
She asked timidly.
他答道 叫我泰德就行
He answered: Call me ted. Oh.
希望没有打扰到你
I don't want to bother you.
-没事 请坐吧  -他说道
-Please, have a seat. -He said.
我教书时间不太长 希望有经验能给分享
I'm fairly new to teaching, and I'm looking for advice.
我每晚练习做讲座 有时还要练两场
Every night I practice giving lectures, sometimes twice.
每当我讲到磁力 呆滞目光遍全场
But when I teach magnetic force, I just see eyeballs glazing.
我问了一圈啥情况 大家都说你教得最棒
I asked around, and people say your lectures are amazing.
超级无敌屌炸棒
Which is really saying something,
毕竟你教的是建筑学嘛 无聊
Because, architecture? Yawn.
泰德想着
And ted thought...
是啊 就跟物理有多好玩一样
Psh, yeah, 'cause physics is so interesting.
接着说
Go on.
就是说你这么会教书
It's just that you're so skilled,
我现在还羽翼未丰
And I'm a relative beginner.
如果不麻烦的话 咱能一起吃顿饭可成
If it isn't too much trouble, can I take you out to dinner?
我希望能收获些技巧 不会耽误你太晚的
I'd love to get some pointers, and I shouldn't keep you late.
你怎么看呀
What do you say?
我怎么看呀
What do I say?
西区泰迪有约会啦
Teddy Westside's got a date!
-好啊  -我们欢呼道
-Hooray! -We cheered.
泰德不坐冷板凳了
Ted's off the bench!
咱家小子重回情场
Our boy's back in the game!
感谢上帝 离上次泰德和女人有约
Thank god, it's been a hundred years
得有一百年过去了吧
Since mosby scored a dame.
上次泰德看到胸部的时候
The last time he saw boobies was
就是在«名扬四海»里的试镜那场戏里了
The screen-test scene in Fame.
泰德前任女朋友
The last girl he dated,
名字好像是右手
I think "Righty" Was her name.
淡定 咱别过分激动
Hold it. Let's not all go crazy
别跟狂暴化了似的
Like some wild berserkers.
如果这只是两个同事一起吃顿饭呢
What if this is just a business meal between co-workers?
泰德想起来以前几次失败的约会
Ted thought back on past failed dates.
天呐 他说得对
Oh, god, that could be true.
有多少次我带着失望的蛋蛋回家睡
How many times have I come home to find my balls are blue?
这全取决于泰德和他那位
It all depends where Ted and his new fetching young Floridian
佛州女士在那条线上的站位
Are standing in relation to that puzzling meridian
国际约会线
Called "The international date line."
你没听错 新学说
That's right, new theory.
-你们问 "那是什么"  -没人问
-"What's that," You ask? -Nobody did.
我就大发慈悲的告诉你们 约会线
I'll now address your query! The date line
也就是欢乐与悲伤的分界
Is the border betwixt happiness and sorrow.
要是在这里 你今晚就回家
On this side, you go home tonight.
要是这里 你就在外过夜
On this side, home tomorrow.
然后 巴尼做的手势太粗鲁
And then, as Barney made some gestures that were rather rude,
泰德离去寻丽萨 心中疑惑止不住
Ted left to go meet Lisa, in a rather puzzled mood.
这算个约会吗
Was this a date?
他不知道自己将要面对什么考验
He simply couldn't tell how he was faring.
然后丽萨出现
Then Lisa showed up.
泰德很高兴看到她衣着惊艳
Ted rejoiced to see what she was wearing.
因为要是出席工作晚餐
For girls at business dinners
女人们不会把事业线开那么低
Don't have necklines that revealing!
但是一个友好的握手让泰德
But then a friendly handshake gave poor Ted
心情跌到谷底
A sinking feeling.
于是 晚餐开始了
And so, the night were on.
然后这个球就这么转啊转啊转
And back and forth, the globe rotated.
泰德的好奇心就这么晃啊晃啊晃
But still, Ted's curiosity was never fully sated.
什么时候是个头
How long could this continue?
他简直就是命运的棋子
He was truly fortune's pawn.
然后丽萨看到了电视
Then Lisa saw the tv.
嘿 洋基队的比赛开始
Hey, the yankees game is on!
-关于棒球  -泰德眼尖注意到
-Of baseball... -Ted observed...
美人似乎颇有料 一手资料皆通晓
...You seem to have some firsthand knowledge.
美女微笑耸肩道
To which the lady shrugged and said...
大学时光多荣耀 垒球娇娃姐之号
I played softball in college.
垒球不过陈腔调 不过如此无夸耀
Now the age-old softball stereotype's just that,
无夸耀
And nothing more.
-漂亮  -洋基跑垒草上飞
Yeah! But as the yankees got a run,
泰德心忧难上垒
Ted feared he wouldn't score.
一朝踏入分界线
For while the date side of the line's
插翅难飞泰德怨
The one we all might guess he's in,
美女投球好手段 小泰无力难称愿
There'll be no joy in tedville if our lisa is a...
漂亮 赢了耶
Yes! We win!
丽萨小酌 轻言道
Then lisa took a drink and said...
此事言及颇轻佻
This may sound kind of random,
小女恋球有蹊跷 若问奴家痴为何
But there actually is a reason for my rabid yankee fandom.
听我一片冰心玉壶道
I guess I'll just be honest here,
座上看官莫讥诮
Though crazy it may seem.
初到宝地事难料 队中一人共春宵
My first week in new york, I dated someone on the team.
队里的谁
Which player?
-人家才不说  -说嘛
-I'm not saying.  -Please?
干嘛八卦 你是记者啊
What are you, a reporter?
泰德心绪飘天边
Ted's mind began to race.
恰逢小二来拿单
The waiter came to take their order.
丽萨朱唇轻启动
As lisa said...
大快朵颐奴不愿 只求意大利式海鲜面
I might like the spaghetti marinara.
可怜泰德心难平 此面莫非另有名
Poor ted just wondered silently...
洋基队版加藤鹰
Mariano rivera?
马里安诺•李维拉 洋基队的王牌终结者 获奖无数
加藤鹰 最有名的岛国动作大片男星
美人此时话未终
And as she said...
此店美味有风评 意式炸鸡传美名
I read this place has great chicken milano.
言者此语无它意 听者闻言有别心
All ted could bring himself to think was:
阿方索•索里阿诺
Alfonso soriano?
阿方索•索里阿诺 洋基队左外野手
等闲小食难填我
I want something hearty.
碳烤味噌鳕鱼又如何
How about blackened miso cod?
是乔•吉拉迪吗
Is it joe girardi?
乔·吉拉迪 扬基队主教练
我的神啊 是强棒罗德里格斯吗
Holy crap, is it a-rod?!
罗德里格斯 全垒打王 曾因与麦当娜有染而天价离婚
好吧 泰德 冷静下来
Okay, ted, calm down.
打起精神来
You've got to get yourself together.
微笑 耍帅
Just smile, be charming,
教授气场 闲淡扯起来
Ooze charisma, talk about the weather.
这个可能是约会呦
For this might be a date,
所以还是有可能偷个情
Which means there might be hanky-panky.
所以老兄 千万一定 冷静 千万不要...
So, dude, be cool, relax, don't even...
快告诉我是哪个货
Just tell me which yankee!
我本来不想说起这个的
I'd rather not discuss this here.
不过既然这样 我也不希望会
But then again, I'd hate...
是这个傻傻的秘密毁了这个约会
To let a silly secret ruin such a lovely date.
既然没什么好回避的
If there's an elephant in the room
我干脆告诉你得了
Why don't we just remove it?
德瑞克•基特
I dated derek jeter.
德瑞克•基特 纽约洋基队队长
有图可作证的
Here's a picture that'll prove it.
泰德小眼屏幕瞟 事出反常必有妖
As ted looked at that cell phone pic,
大石两块落心底
There were two things he reckoned.
确为约会能有炮
This definitely was a date,
此女却非常人消
But there wouldn't be a second.
睁眼看 效果显
See? It worked.
老爸押韵词款款 送我小宝梦甜甜
I said some rhymes, and out my boy did conk.
路漫漫 心安安
Now let's enjoy the ride.
会开车不 傻逼
Move, jackass!
可悲峰转又路回 重做新词再入睡
Okay, I need a brand-new tale to silence marvin's chatter.
才送清风歌一曲 轻渡舟楫君难为
I don't know, that last one had some sketchy subject matter.
言直情真君莫怪 吞云吐雾实不该
Forgive me, but before you got here, did you smoke a joint?
淼淼烟熏儿难耐
You don't tell kids a tale that crass!
老爸手指轻点赞
I guess he had a point.
老父此事也了然
I know, I said some things that were,
如君语 狭媚之事不宜言
As you say, kind of questionable.
肺腑之言 马文是小男
The truth is, children marvin's age
尚且年幼记忆浅
Aren't really that impressionable.
如你我 也枉然
Do you remember anything from when you were this small?
小时多健忘 唯不忘相思 恰如我小时 唯记南瓜拾
Pumpkin picking at age three is the first thing I recall.
嗯哼
Hmm. Huh.
此时确难记 我同意
He won't remember this. I guess it's true.
如我心意
It better be.
否则他日需求医
Or else we'll end up paying
有道是 多花米
Through the nose for marvin's therapy.
你我二人多戏谑 在下周公尚有约
Okay, buddy, nice chat, but I think I need a break.
正解
Great idea.
此事尚未完
After this story!
罗宾蛋糕盘
Robin takes the cake.
吃相略难堪
Once in an east side bakery,
众人围观围一团
Your debonair aunt robin was making other customers think,
谁家有女难嫁汉
"Geez, who let this slob in?"
云淡风轻爱看看 罗宾猛塞才不管
She didn't care about their stares, or who was looking on.
落花流水谁无意
She'd just broke up with...
凯文
Kevin.
不对 是盖尔 还是史酷比
No, gael. Or scooby?
还是唐
Don?
若说罗宾吃相赞
Now, sometimes,
遥看瀑布挂前川
When it rains it pours,
已惊岩下雪如尘
And sometimes, it starts snowing,
大珠小珠落玉盘
For as cream filling hit her shirt...
好久不见
Hey, robin, how's it going?
罗宾抬头定睛看 正是西蒙混帐男
'twas simon, her ex-boyfriend
此君来自加拿大 青梅竹马有前缘
From her younger days in canada,
士别三日刮目看 此刻西蒙
But now, he looked quite different...
呃
Um...
押韵
Rhyme.
呃 我想想
Uh... Thinking. Uh...
刚刚我文思泉涌停不下来啊
I've just been handed a news flash.
"加拿大"这个词不押韵啊
The word "Canada" is unrhymeable.
随便说上一句话
It's easier to-- I don't know--
喝醉酒骑头牛都比押韵简单啊
get drunk and try to climb a bull.
但是加拿大 哎呀 芸芸众生你随便问吧
But canada, damn it, ask any man on the planet
你且看他结结巴巴
and watch their stammerin' stamina
想方设法把"加拿大"塞进他的话
as they clamor and cram it into the middle of a sentence.
但他就是不得其法
For a shot at repentance,
再悔恨也没办法 只能将此难题留给后人解答
pass the problem on to all their non-rhyming descendants.
我至今都没见过谁能把韵脚押上"加拿大"
I've never met anyone who could clean up after Canada,
但我那家住布朗克斯的叔叔托尼做到啦
except my uncle tony from the bronx.
他只是个门卫哪
He's a janitor.
臭显摆
Show-off.
西蒙 见到你真高兴
Simon. Nice to see you.
你来纽约干嘛啊
So, what brings you to New York?
-我搬到纽约来了  -是吗 真的啊
-I live here now. -What? Really?
-是呢  -真好
-Yeah. -That's great.
能给我把叉子吗
Can I get a fork?
尽管西蒙终日游手好闲
He'd always been a deadbeat
不修边幅 说话办事不着边
and your classic hoser phony.
可罗宾眼见今日的西蒙衣着光鲜不似从前 心中顿生许多愁念
But seeing simon all cleaned up hit robin like a zamboni.
她将他仔仔细细上下打量
And as she looked him up and down,
罗宾年轻的心不禁一阵悲伤
young robin felt a tingle.
西蒙是否终于脱胎换骨
Had simon blossomed finally?
若果真如此 我和他又能否将破镜修补
And if so, was he single?
真是太好了
So great.
她柔声细语身姿婀娜 媚眼狂送秋波
She purred, whilst batting her eyelashes like a flooze.
是很好 我跟露易丝•马什订婚了
Yup, I'm engaged to Louise Marsh,
我们家里有超豪华按摩浴缸呢
and our pad's got a jacuzz!
糕点店瞬间天旋地转 罗宾好似走在云端
The bakery spinned, the floor dropped out.
空气都被冻结 充满不安
The air was thick as syrup.
罗宾只觉头晕目眩 呼吸困难
Poor robin swooned, she couldn't breathe.
泪水即将决堤
Her eyes began to tear up.
正当她欲鼓起勇气逃离此地
And as she tried to stammer some excuse
西蒙一语 让她跌到谷底
to get away, simon said:
我们的结婚蛋糕是不是超级牛逼
Our wedding cake is pretty bitchin', eh?
此时 罗宾心中腾升起无限恨意
And so was born the worst idea poor robin's ever had.
门扉轻叩 泰德应门
And on ted's door there came a rapping.
我干了件非常不好的事
I did something bad.
罗宾将事件原委一一道来
As robin told her tale,
泰德便知 她犯了何等严重的错误
Ted knew she'd made a massive boo-boo,
因为偷拿别人的结婚蛋糕是多么地无可饶恕
for stealing someone's wedding cake is terribly bad juju.
罗宾 你变成现在这样 我真是看不下去
Robin, I'm beside myself to see what you've become!
你必须马上把蛋糕还回去
You must return this cake at once!
-我做不到  -怎么做不到
-I can't! -Why not?
因为...
'cause...
好吃
Yum.
泰德无语叹息 他从未见过比这更恶毒的行为
Ted gasped, for he had never seen a brazen act so vicious.
罗宾虽然懊悔 但是...
Robin felt remorse, and yet...
我的天 太好吃了我停不下嘴
Oh, god, this is delicious!
于是一生二 二生三 三生无穷 罗宾已经吃了17口蛋糕
So one piece led to two, then three, then five, then 17.
她就像只饥肠辘辘的狼人 蛋糕在她口里被瓦解掉
She savaged that poor cake like some rapacious wolverine.
她吃 她吞 她咬 她嚼 一个疯狂的晚上就此来到
Eating, gobbling, munching, so the frenzied night wore on.
妈妈尚未赶到
And by the time your mom arrived,
已经没了一半蛋糕
the cake was halfway gone.
我收到消息立刻就过来了
I came as soon as I got word.
情况有多糟糕
So how bad is the damage?
你自己看吧 她正在上演"疯狂的食道"
See for yourself the product of her cake-in-gullet crammage!
我已经吃了半个蛋糕了吗
Half a cake?
我都干了什么啊
What have I done?!
我的行为不会被世人原谅
The world shall not forgive it!
这罪恶的一天将永远留在耻辱柱上
This day will live in infamy.
我一生都不能摆脱这个罪状
I never shall outlive it!
我已堕落至此
For I have become
我化悲愤为食量 一口一口吃掉忧伤
the girl that eats her feelings, don't mistake it.
在我坐坏这把椅子之前 我最好还是立刻离场
I think I need to get out of this chair before I break it.
瞎说 瞎想 别乱讲
Nonsense! Hogwash! Balderdash!
你妈妈的热心一如既往
Said mommy, with great fervor.
你不能现在停下 难道你不明白吗
You can't stop now, for don't you see?
对不知情的人来讲 你并非什么青春疼痛文学里
To the uninformed observer, you're not some sad cliche,
满心伤痛的怨女
some loser from a chick-lit story.
你是罗宾 吃完剩下的半个蛋糕 荣誉就属于你
You're robin, and you're half a wedding cake away from glory!
你要是现在停下 那西蒙就是赢家
If you quit now, then simon wins.
而故事的结局就是
The tale comes to a stop
罗宾偶遇旧爱 惊慌失措
at how you saw an ex, freaked out,
还偷了糕点 犯下过错
and robbed a pastry shop.
你要是狠狠心 亲爱的
If you have the guts, my dear,
现在就是时候火力全开
it's time to get empowered
把蛋糕吃光
and be remembered for this
让你的英名千古流芳
sweet behemoth you devoured.
多年以后
And years from now,
游吟诗人会为你作诗吟唱
the troubadour will raise his voice and sing
歌颂罗宾是如何偷拿蛋糕
of the time that robin took the cake.
并且把这东西
and ate the whole...
吃了个
damned...
精光
thing.
罗宾再一次深深深呼吸
Once more into the breach she surged,
泰德和妈妈给她加油打气
as ted and mommy cheered
一口又一口 那罪恶的蛋糕塔 高度越来越低
and bite by bite the towering confection disappeared.
有朋自远方来目睹这场战役
Some friends were called to come and watch.
无人需要多做努力
And no one had to beg,
吃蛋糕派对的声名便远播千里
it soon became a party.
巴尼甚至搬来了一桶酒 此乃助兴神器
Barney even got a keg.
左一叉右一勺 罗宾狂吃法式香草
Forkful after forkful, Robin guzzled french vanilla,
那动静简直就像是猩猩般狂躁
making noises not unlike those made by a gorilla.
加油啊 罗宾 吃了它
Come on, Robin, finish it.
你妈妈的谆谆教诲回荡在罗宾的耳旁
Mom's exhortations rang
就像阿波罗在洛基对战克鲁伯•朗时一直在旁指导一样
like Apollo coaching Rocky 'gainst a frosted clubber lang.
啊 «洛基4» 我的最爱
Oh, Rocky iv, my favorite.
不对 第四部是跟俄国人打的
No, no, iv is with the russians.
不对 第四部是洛基因为脑震荡
No, iv's the one where he talks weird
整个人说话都怪怪的
because of his concussions.
-他好像在每部电影里都那样  -打住
-I think that's all of them. -Hey now,
不要争了 就是第四部
no need to be discordant. It's rocky iv.
-不 是第三部  -错 是第二部
-No, iii. -No, ii.
管它哪部不哪部
It's really not important.
最后时分人共鉴 最后一块举嘴边
At last young Robin raised the final bite up to her lips.
人群顿时寂无言
The crowd grew still.
只闻巴尼吃薯片
The only sound was barney eating chips.
蛋糕剩最后一口
Just one bite left.
这一幕就如«铁窗喋血»中的硬汉老卢
Hey, this is like that scene from cool hand luke.
五十鸡蛋轻轻松松吃下肚
You know, "My boy can eat 50 eggs." Right?
分分钟都要吐
She's gonna puke.
但罗宾没有吐
But robin did not puke.
她吃完那口直立而起 面带骄傲
She ate that bite and stood up, proud.
等下 我还没完呢
Wait. I'm not done yet.
对着惊魂未定的人群 大声嘶喊道
She shouted, to the startled crowd.
我秒杀了这个婚礼蛋糕
I've bested this here wedding cake.
我非常乐意获此荣耀
I'll gladly wear that crown.
既然挑战已经做到
But now that I have done that task,
那也是时候将它冲刷掉
It's time to wash it down.
今晚实在太美好
For it's been such an awesome night,
只有一个办法画上句号
There's just one way to cap it.
我要把这桶酒全都喝掉
I'm going to drink this entire keg.
巴尼 把酒开好
Okay, barney, tap it.
哦 哇噢
Oh! Wow.
嘿咻 嘿咻
Hup. Ho-o, oh.
当晚大家记住的 不再是罗宾被抛弃
And now that night's remembered not for robin getting dumped
而是我们送她去洗胃的记忆
But as the night we took her in to get her stomach pumped.
快看啊
And look at that,
小天使睡过去了 大家
The little angel's sleeping soundly, gus.
看起来我们的问题像是...
Looks like our problems...
别一车占俩道
Pick a lane!
我恨这巴士恨到家
I hate this stupid bus.
马尔文 恐怕今晚要彻底沦陷
Marvin, I'm afraid this night is not much of a winner.
我们堵在半路 还得错过整个预演晚宴
Stuck in traffic, now we've missed the whole rehearsal dinner.
我希望我是对的 你对这段事情没有记忆
I pray that I was right and that you'll have no memory
LIE即Long Island Expressway
地狱般的长岛高速乘车记
Of this godforsaken ride down the congested LIE.
至少有一点我能肯定
At least we know one thing for sure:
今天也不可能更倒霉了吧 想必
Things can't get worse, I swear.
永别了 堵死马桶的卷饼 爽啊
Adios, truck stop burrito. Ooh!
洗手间别去
Do not go in there.
好吧 再给你说一个 我试着好好讲
Okay, one more story, and I'll try to tell it pretty.
巴尼•斯丁森的传说
The tale of barney stinson,
纽约城花花公子之大帝
Player king of new york city.
很久以前 我们去酒吧怡情小酌
Once upon a time, we all went out to get our drink on.
此时进来了一个女孩
When who should walk in but a girl
粉色毛衣紧身惹火
With sweater tight and pink on.
她点了一杯啤酒
She ordered up a beer.
想必你也已经知道结局
I think you see where this is going.
如同巴尼意味深长的一句
As barney put it, oh so eloquently:
遇玉欲御
Boy-oy-oy-oing.
他起身走向女孩准备下手
He rose to go approach this girl commanding such intrigue
你妈妈突然打断说
When mommy interrupted:
哥们 你完全不是她的对手
Dude, she's way out of your league.
美国Hooters餐厅 小孩子去了一定把持不住
她没穿小热裤 也没套挤胸衣
She's not in daisy dukes, nor squeezed into a hooters tee.
而且她钥匙链上也没挂什么健身VIP
And I don't see a curves membership dangling from her key.
她不用古铜喷雾
She has no glaring spray tan,
也没纹独角兽
no unicorn tattoos.
她在品啜夏敦埃 没在猛灌樱桃味酒
She's sipping chardonnay, not pounding cherry-flavored booze.
她没花枝招展 也没在拨弄头发
Her makeup isn't running, she's not playing with her hair.
她几乎不可能让你把那家伙放进那
There's very little chance she'll let you put it anywhere.
我接受你的挑战 莉莉
Your challenge is accepted, lil.
不存在小妞太过漂亮
There is no girl too pretty,
因为我是巴尼•斯丁森
For I am barney stinson,
纽约城花花公子之大帝
Player king of new york city.
你不能自封为帝
You can't anoint yourself the king,
就像那个混蛋 勒布朗
Just like that jerk, lebron.
他都离开骑士队三年了
He left the cavs three years ago.
兄弟 放下吧 忘掉过往
Bro, give it up, move on.
所以 为什么我是大帝 问得好
So why am I king? Glad you asked.
-我们没有  -从没问过
-We didn't. -Never do.
我要讲述这一切的源头
It's origin story time.
相信我 字字是真不会错
And trust me, every word is true.
很早之前的清晨 我从一个猎物身边醒来
One morning long ago, I woke up next to a conquest.
如此多的闪光 她的咪咪
So many great things 'bout this girl: Her boobs,
她的胸部 她的大奶
Her rack, her chest.
她饥渴难耐
She had a thirst for action,
年轻的巴尼填满了她欲壑
And young Barney was a-quenchin' it.
这和剧情有关吗
Is this important to the story?
没啊 顺便一提图个乐
No, just thought I'd mention it.
当我甩掉大波辣妹 正要离开
As I departed, having bid this busty babe buh-bye,
我驻足观望 不禁疑惑起来
I stopped and looked around, and wondered:
妈现在在哪儿
Where the hell am I?
路牌写着22街 疑惑瞬间拜拜
The sign read 22nd street, and my concern decreased
直到阴风将树枝吹向一旁 露出"东"字牌
Until a cold wind blew a branch aside, Revealing: "East."
在东边 不要啊
The east side. No.
我都做了些什么
Wh-what have I done?
我结结巴巴的说着
I stammered with chagrin.
接下来一个黑色的轿车停在我面前
Just then a black sedan pulled up...
-你是巴尼  -是
-You barney? -Yeah.
上车
Get in.
有一句真的吗
Is any of this true?
当然 现在 坐稳了朋友们
Of course. Now, hang on to your "Chayers."
那一天我被召至
For that day I was called before...
花花公子最高议会
The high council of players.
先生们 十分感谢大家的出席
Gentlemen, for your attendance here, our deepest thanks.
我很遗憾地说 议会的队伍中混入了偷猎者的踪迹
I'm sad to say, this council has a poacher in its ranks.
这位巴尼
For barney here
泡了一个他领土之外的美女
Picked up a girl outside his territory.
东区
The east side
是燕尾服查理的领地
Is tuxedo charlie's turf.
他生气了呢
He's mad.
真实的故事
True story.
2004年的协议清楚地规定
The agreement of 2004 quite clearly did define
第五大道是我们猎场的分界线
Fifth avenue to be our hunting grounds' dividing line.
你西区里的学生妹我毫不染指
Your west side college girls are not the slip I park my boat in.
所以你应当知道
So you should know
我东区里初涉世事的少女对你严格禁止
My east side debutantes are quite verboten.
议会成员们
members of the council...
兄弟们... 谁都不希望硝烟四起
Bros... Nobody wants a war.
我当然没有忘记04年的协议
Of course I've not forgotten the agreement of '04.
但我能说什么呢 一次失足而已
What can I say? A bonehead move.
为此申辩吗 我无能为力
Defend it? I'm not able.
但是 兄弟们 我难道没有
But, bros, have I not been a bro
对在座的各位兄弟尽忠尽力
To each bro at this table?
我来自布鲁克林的小伙伴 泡菜坛•鲍勃
My friend from brooklyn, pickle jar bob,
会证明我的情谊
Will give some validation.
记得那个年轻的游客吗
Remember that young tourist
寻找宾州车站的那一位
Who was looking for penn station?
她刚从波士顿前来 拥有魔鬼般的身材
She'd just come in from boston, had a wicked good-in-bed look.
红钩 位于纽约布鲁克林
我给她错误的指引 让她走向了红钩地带
I gave her bad directions and she ended up in Red Hook.
-闭嘴 巴尼  -悠着点 布朗克斯•多尼
-Shut up, barney. -Whoa, bronx donnie,
咱们不要激动着急
Let's not get excited.
燕尾服查理不是这里唯一一枚受害者
Tuxedo charlie's not the only one here who's been slighted.
你告诉她你是基特 好将她诱至你的床第
You told her you were Jeter in your quest to lie upon her.
德瑞克•基特 美国职棒大联盟选手 纽约洋基队队长
假扮洋基队员是我的专利
Impersonating yankees is my thing.
你难道没有一点信誉
Have you no honor?
先生们 请安静 咱们不要把
Gentlemen, please, let's not blow
这缓和的关系弃之谷底
This détente to smithereens.
议会致意委员长比尔
Council recognizes captain bill,
Queen双关皇后和纽约皇后区
来自皇后那边的兄弟
Our bro from Queens.
多谢
Thank you.
你们都认识我
You all know me,
你们都尊重我的游戏
And you all respect my game.
我穿着飞行员服 泡妞于行李提取处
I dress up like a pilot and meet girls in baggage claim.
在我那从61街和伍德赛德启程的漫长地铁里
And on my long-ass subway ride from 61st and Woodside,
我想到了让大家和睦相处的妙计
I came up with a plan to keep you on each other's good side.
巴尼 你委屈了这两位兄弟
Barney, you have wronged these two.
对于这个他们快输了的游戏
So, for the game they're losing,
你必须为其每人提供
you now must grant them each
一个他们喜欢的西区美女
A west side hottie of their choosing.
开什么玩笑你
You're kidding.
这就是最后决议
That's the settlement?
别这样 这也太过傻比
Come on, that's rather silly.
先生们 你们怎么说
Gentlemen, what say you?
我要罗宾
I want robin.
我要莉莉
I want lily.
搞笑呢 布朗克斯•多尼
Please. Bronx donnie?
想与我同床根本没戏
No chance he could get me in the sack.
告诉那个黑手党 有地儿让他抽人去
Tell that mafioso I know something he can whack.
女士们 你们不用担心
Ladies, don't you worry,
你们的淑女之腿可放心紧闭
Your fair legs can all stay closed.
因为幸运的是 我的提案 他们最终满意
'cause luckily they took the counteroffer I proposed.
好了 先生们
Well, gentlemen,
看样子我多说无益
It seems there's nothing I can say to sway you.
查理 多尼
Charlie, donnie,
废话少说 我会补偿于你
Say no more, I gladly will repay you.
卡洛塔 上香槟
Carlotta, some champagne.
休会之前让我们举杯共饮
Let's toast before we all adjourn.
敬咪咪
To boobies.
哦 对了
Oh, and b-t-dub,
你们都中毒啦
Y'all just drank poison.
傻眼了吧
Ha-burn.
至此 朋友们 我就成为了...
And thus, my friends, I have become,
虽是利用略血腥的方式
Through methods somewhat gory
纽约城花花公子之大帝
The player king of new york city.
完毕
The end.
真实的故事
True story.
好吧 挺好的
Well, that was great.
你的小故事戳中了我们的笑点
Your little story tickled all our ribs.
但你犯了一个错误 先生
But one mistake you made, sir,
那就是忘了预定在先
Was forgetting to call dibs.
不 这不公平
No! Not fair.
我才是玩家大帝
But I'm the king.
-打扮也帅得多  -不好意思啊兄弟
-And such a better dresser. -Sorry, dude,
这就是我对于
But that's revenge
丽萨教授事件的报复
For lisa the professor.
再喝一轮吧
Let's have another round.
你妈妈说道
Your mommy said.
我们又喝了几许
And so we had one.
夜晚还在继续 我必须要说
The night wore on, and I must say,
这是个不错的经历
It wasn't a half bad one.
如此的回忆 我们年轻快乐的心
What memories. Our young and happy hearts
火焰般热情
Were hot as fire.
那些日子仿佛发生在上个世纪
Feels like a lifetime since those days.
抱歉同志们
Sorry, folks,
爆胎了
Flat tire.
哦 别这样啊
oh, come on.
这下我再也到不了南塔克特岛了
Now I'm never gonna make it to nantucket.
看 烟花在空中绽放
Oh, look a fireworks display.
小火箭发出耀眼红光
Some rockets red glare action.
谢天谢地
Thank god.
我还以为是我青光眼滴眼液的作用呢
Thought my glaucoma drops were causing a reaction.
马尔文 抱歉整个旅行像屎一样
Marvin, I'm so sorry this whole journey's been a bummer.
很快你就能回到妈咪的怀抱 温暖如夏日阳光
Soon you'll be right back in mommy's arms, as warm as summer.
不幸的是 当我们登记入住酒店的那刻开始
But sadly while your troubles stop once we get to the inn
你的烦恼烟消云散 而我的麻烦却刚刚开场
The moment we arrive is when my troubles will begin.
有时爸爸做事荒唐
Sometimes daddies screw up,
有时妈妈脾气暴涨
Sometimes mommies get upset.
但我真心希望这个周末的记忆 能让你快快遗忘
I really hope this weekend is a memory you'll forget.
快抬起头吧 看看烟花绽放 余烬飞扬
So look up at those fireworks, enjoy the falling embers...
孩子们 这就是你们马尔文哥哥记忆中的第一件事
And that, kids, is the very first thing your cousin marvin remembers.
女士们先生们 还有一个小时...
Gentlemen and ladies, it'll be an hour or so...
卡车就能来到这儿牵引大巴了
before the truck gets here to give our broken bus a tow.
与此同时呢 我们还是轻松惬意点吧
So in the meantime I suggest we all get nice and cozy.
我们还得在这待会儿
We're gonna be here for a while.
英语儿歌 同时也是一种儿童玩的游戏
围着玫瑰绕圈圈吗
Uh, ring-around-the-rosy?
好啊
Yeah!
你觉得这儿离远汉普顿旅馆有多远呢
How far do you suppose it is to the farhampton inn?
我觉得还有五英里吧
I'd say about five miles away.
不要啊
Oh, no.
你奸笑是什么意思呢
What's with the grin?
然后马修仰望天空
Then Marshall looked up heavenward,
以夜空中第一颗星为名庄严发誓
And swore by night's first star
说出了他马上就会后悔的五个字
Five simple words he'd soon regret:
我能走到那
I can walk that far.
Marshall vs. The Machines by Jason Segel
HIMYM字幕组 谢谢观看